Joshua Walton

jswalton.dev@gmail.com (843)-323-2485 3108 Newell St. San Diego, CA 92106

Summary

A full stack software developer with experience in Java Enterprise technologies, Scala, Play Framework, AngularJS, Amazon Web Services, and mobile. Always working within agile software development life cycle frameworks (SCRUM), and focused on delivering tested solutions to customer driven requirements. Strong communication skills and a desire to engage with fellow team members to collaborate and learn more. Pursuing web application, mobile application, or backend development employment opportunities that give room to grow knowledge and abilities as a developer.

Experience

Software Developer at Dispute Resolution Data

July 2016 - Present - Web Application Development/ Production Operations

Junior Software Developer at SPARC, LLC

December 2011 - July 2016 (4 years 8 months) Web Application Development

Intern at SPARC, LLC

March 2011 - December 2011 (10 months) Mobile Application Development

Projects

Dispute Resolution Data (DRD)

January 2015 to Present

I am responsible for the development and maintenance of Dispute Resolution Data's web application. The mission of Dispute Resolution Data (DRD) is to enhance and grow the field

of dispute resolution through access to trusted aggregated data. My principal duties were to help with driving requirements, infrastructure development (AWS), application development, production operations & deployments, and testing. DRD achieves its development success through the use of stateless web architecture (Play Framework/Scala) and AngularJS front-end. I am the principal developer for DRD.

Veterans Benefit Management System

November 2011 to June 2014

I was responsible for the iterative development of new functionality as well as maintenance of existing pieces of VBMS, while using agile development methodologies (SCRUM). VBMS is a paperless claims management system that aims to reduce the number of claims in the VA backlog by 2015. Large milestones achieved include the design and implementation of document viewing functionality, implementation of letter correspondence functionality, implementation of SOAP and REST web services, and many pieces of UI functionality. I worked with technologies such as J2EE (Weblogic), JPA, Spring Framework, and more.

Education

College of Charleston

B.S., Computer Science, 2007 - 2011

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency), Spanish(Professional proficiency)

Interests

Travel, Surfing, Skydiving